

Joe Barber^{· 3rd}

Application Engineer & Technical Sales at Direct Part Production

Denver, Colorado, United states Contact info

600+ connections

Message

More

DPP Direct Particular

Direct Part Production



University of Denver

Featured



Our New HP MJF

Directpartsolution.com

Always one step ahead we provide the best for our customer so what new for you?

About

You could say I act as the bridge between our clients and the engineer's R&D centres. I am responsible for generating new business opportunities for Direct Part Production through application development.

I like to say my job is, "To make sure that the design is optimized for the process, and make sure the process is then optimized for the design."

I love to educate customers on the benefits of new technology such as HP Multi Jet Fusion, and then help them choose the correct parts they need.

I take customer input and sales information to design or redesign, develop, test, and implement complex problems and applications then optimize the design and process for cost and quality. I provide technical support and expertise to customers by testing applications and responding to feedback. I respond to customer issues, solves issues, perform customer sales/presentations.

Due to my enduring passion for engineering, I enjoy building upon my knowledge of various computer programs that I can utilise to further my career in the industry.

I also enjoy playing several sports, including tennis and indoor hockey.



Activity

183 followers

Joe Barber commented on this post • 1mo

Go Pete Sampras!



2 comments

Joe Barber commented on this post • 2mo

I work with the Nathaniel Haase the Process Engineer to ensure the design and process for the customers design is optimized as much as possible



Experience



Production Manager

Full-time

Application Engineer & Technical Sales

May 2004 - Present Stamford, Connecticut, United States

Technical Sales

Feb 2000 – May 2004 · 4 yrs 3 mos Stamford, Connecticut, United States

Education



University of Denver

Batchelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science & Information Systems 2000 - 2004

Courses

Iron CAD

AutoCAD, Fusion 360,

Solidworks Advanced Training

Creo Parametric 3D Modeling Software

Languages

English

Native or bilingual proficiency